<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <!--- Reusable Strings -->
    <string name="ok"> OK </string>
    <string name="cancel"> Cancel </string>
    <string name="edit"> Edit </string>
    <string name="app_name">WeightWatch</string>
    <string name="update">update</string>
    <string name="profil">Profil</string>
    <string name="info">Info</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome</string>
    <string name="permission_not_granted">Permission was not granted</string>


    <!-- toolbar menu -->
    <string name="menu_delete">Delete Data</string>
    <string name="menu_backup">Backup</string>
    <string name="menu_help">Help</string>
    <string name="menu_option">Option</string>

    <!-- Options -->
    <string name="options_notification_title">Notification Settings</string>
    <string name="options_notification_enable">Enable Notifications</string>
    <string name="options_notification_morning">Morning Reminder</string>
    <string name="options_notification_evening">Evening Summary</string>
    <string name="options_notification_blocked">Notifications are blocked for this App by the System.\nPlease enable them in your phone settings.</string>
    <string name="options_other_settings">Other Settings</string>

    <!-- insert Weight -->
    <string name="insert_weight_title">Pls insert new weight value!</string>
    <string name="insert_weight_kg">kilo</string>
    <string name="insert_weight_gram">,  gram </string>

    <!-- Navigation Menu MainActivity -->
    <string name="backup_information_title">Backup succesfull</string>
    <string name="backup_information">The Data was writen int the Application dir/Data.</string>
    <string name="backup_information_fail">The backup failed, pls try again. Check that all needed permissions are given.</string>

    <!--- Graph Strings!-->
    <string name="graph_legend_weight">WEIGHT</string>
    <string name="graph_legend_base_cal">DAILY CAL. BURN</string>
    <string name="graph_title">%1$d day graph View</string>

    <!--- Weekplaner Strings !-->
    <string name="sunday">Sunday</string>
    <string name="monday">Monday</string>
    <string name="tuesday">Tuesday</string>
    <string name="wednesday">Wednesday</string>
    <string name="thursday">Thursday</string>
    <string name="friday">Friday</string>
    <string name="saturday">Saturday</string>
    <string name="weekplaner_time">time</string>
    <string name="planner_time_date">hh/date</string>
    <string name="planner_legend_1">current hour</string>
    <string name="planner_legend_2">normal cal intake</string>
    <string name="planner_legend_3">high cal intake</string>
    <string name="planner_legend_4">Cal Fast: 16h+"</string>


    <!--- Overview Strings!-->
    <string name="overview_cal_day">Calories day</string>
    <string name="overview_cal_left">Calories left</string>
    <string name="overview_bmi">BMI:</string>
    <string name="overview_weight">Weight:</string>

    <!--- edit Strings!-->
    <string name="edit_weight">weight</string>
    <string name="edit_meals">meals</string>


    <!--- InsertWindow Strings!-->
    <string name="insert_meal">Please insert your meal and calories:</string>
    <string name="hint_insert_what">Please insert description</string>
    <string name="hint_insert_cal">Please insert cal amount</string>
    <string name="insert_date_format">Date (YYYY-MM-DD)</string>
    <string name="insert_time_format">Time (HH:mm)</string>
    <string name="insert_no_input">Please enter name and calorie</string>

    <!--- CreateUser window Strings !-->
    <string name="createUser_Title">Create new user</string>
    <string name="createUser_name">Please insert Name</string>
    <string name="createUser_weight">Please insert weight in Kg</string>
    <string name="createUser_CalUse">Estimated calories \nneeded per day:</string>
    <string name="createUser_CalTarget"></string>
    <string name="createUser_height">Please insert height in cm</string>
    <string name="createUser_target_weight">Please insert target weight</string>
    <string name="createUser_Age">Please insert Age</string>
    <string name="createUser_Bmi">Your BMI is: </string>
    <string name="createUser_targetBmi">Your BMI at target weight is: </string>
    <string name="createUser_Man">man</string>
    <string name="createUser_female">female</string>
    <string name="createUser_activity_low">low</string>
    <string name="createUser_activity_medium">medium</string>
    <string name="createUser_activity_high">high</string>
    <string name="createUser_activity_label">activity:</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit">EditActivity</string>
    <string name="createUser_toolbar_title">New User</string>
    <string name="createUser_data_use">Insert data are only locally saved. The app needs the data for calculating your daily calorie burn rate. You can change this data later. (Menu -> Profile -> Edit Profile)</string>

    <!-- Delete Data Dialogbox Strings !-->
    <string name="delet_dialogbox_warning">Are you sure that you want to delete User and all data? Data can not be recovered.\n
    (Backup data wont be deleted and must be deleted from Application folder /Data)</string>
    <string name="delet_dialogbox_title">Delete Data Warning</string>

    <!-- Edite Activity Strings !-->
    <string name="editActivity_toolbarMessage">Edit</string>
    <!-- Profile Activity Strings !-->
    <string name="profilActivity_toolbarMessage">Profil</string>
    <string name="profile_target">Your target is:</string>
    <string name="profile_calroies">Your daily Cal use is:</string>
    <string name="profile_bmi">Your Bmi is:</string>

    <string name="profile_progress_greeting_good">
        Congratulations on your progress!\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_greeting_bad">
        You can do it, don\'t give up!\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_weight">
        Your current weight is %1$.1f kg, and since %2$s, you\'ve lost %3$.1f kg.
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_weight_7days">
        The last 7 days amounted to a weight change of %1$.1f kg.
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_weight_result_good">
        Weight fluctuations during a diet are normal, but it\'s always encouraging to see some progress.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_weight_result_bad">
        Weight fluctuations during a diet are normal, and it\'s normal to face challenges along the way.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_cal">
        You maintained an average calorie intake of %1$.1f per day, which means you had an average calorie deficit of %2$.1f per day.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_intermittent">
        You\'ve successfully practiced intermittent fasting on %1$d out of the last 7 days.
        Intermittent fasting has been shown to improve metabolism and promote weight loss.
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_intermittent_bad">
        Intermittent fasting may be difficult but the benefits should outweigh the difficulties, so let\'s do our best.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_intermittent_good">
        Keep up the good work!\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_encourage_good">
        Remember, weight loss is a unique journey, and results may vary. Stay consistent, stay positive, and let\'s achieve your health goals
        together!\n\nKeep up the great work, and you\'ll reach your target weight of %1$.1f in around %2$d days!
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_encourage_bad">
        Remember, weight loss is a unique journey, and results may vary. Stay consistent, stay positive, stay committed to your goals,
        and try implementing intermittent fasting and an calorie deficit in the next 7days. Stay committed to your journey,
        and with time, effort, and our app\'s support, you\'ll achieve your health goals!\n\nKeep up the great work so you can reach
        your weight goal of %1$.1f.
    </string>
    <string name="profile_progress_message_new_user">
        Welcome to our weight and calorie tracker app!\n\nAs a new user, we don\'t have enough data yet to
        provide a further information here. But don\'t worry, you\'re taking the first step towards a healthier lifestyle!\n\nSet your health goals, track your
        weight and calorie intake regularly, and practice intermittent fasting to see positive changes.\n\nRemember, it\'s all about consistency and dedication.
        Stay committed to your journey, and with time, effort, and our app\'s support, you\'ll achieve your health goals!\n\nKeep up the great work, and let\'s
        embark on this transformative journey together!
    </string>

    <!--Info Activity Strings-->
    <string name="info_toolbar_text">Info</string>

    <string name="essay_weight_loss">
        The Key to Effective Weight Loss: Calorie Deficit and the 16+8 Approach\n\nIn today\'s fast-paced world, weight loss has become a prevailing concern for many individuals seeking to improve their health and well-being. While various methods and strategies exist, two crucial aspects stand out as fundamental contributors to successful weight loss: maintaining a calorie deficit and following the 16+8 intermittent fasting approach.\n\n1. Calorie Deficit:\n\na. Energy balance:\nWeight loss occurs when the body\'s energy expenditure surpasses its energy intake. This prompts the body to utilize stored fat as a source of fuel, ultimately leading to weight loss.
        \n\nb. Calorie tracking:\nMonitoring daily caloric intake and expenditure is essential for maintaining a calorie deficit. By accurately assessing the nutritional content of food and tracking physical activity, individuals can make informed decisions to ensure a sustained deficit.\n\nc. Balanced nutrition:\nWhile it\'s crucial to create a calorie deficit, it is equally important to maintain a balanced diet. Prioritizing nutrient-dense foods, including lean proteins, whole grains, fruits, and vegetables, can support overall health and provide essential vitamins and minerals while keeping calorie intake in check.\n\n2. 16+8 Intermittent Fasting:
        \n\na. Enhanced fat burning:\nBy extending the fasting period, the body exhausts its readily available energy from food, prompting the utilization of stored fat for fuel. This promotes fat burning and aids in weight loss.\n\nb. Insulin regulation:\nIntermittent fasting can improve insulin sensitivity, which helps regulate blood sugar levels. This, in turn, reduces the risk of insulin resistance and supports better weight management.\n\nc. Appetite control:\nRestricting the eating window to 8 hours can help regulate hunger hormones and curb excessive snacking. This can result in better portion control, reduced calorie intake, and ultimately contribute to weight loss goals.
        \n\nAchieving sustainable weight loss requires a multifaceted approach that includes creating a calorie deficit and implementing effective strategies. Maintaining a calorie deficit through mindful calorie tracking and a balanced diet is essential for consistent weight loss. Additionally, the 16+8 intermittent fasting approach offers a beneficial framework for enhancing fat burning, regulating insulin levels, and controlling appetite.\n\nIt is important to note that weight loss journeys are individualized, and what works for one person may not work for another. Consulting a healthcare professional or a registered dietitian is recommended to personalize weight loss plans and ensure overall well-being. With dedication, patience, and a holistic approach, achieving and maintaining a healthy weight becomes an attainable goal for everyone.
    </string>

    <!--Help Activity Strings-->
    <string name="help_toolbar_text">Help</string>
    <string name="help_a_title">A. Overview information</string>
    <string name="help_a1_info">Greetings and Username</string>
    <string name="help_a2_info">Four icons to indicate your current BMI, your current weight, your daily calorie burn rate and the max calorie you can still intake today before you gain weight.</string>
    <string name="help_a3_info">Press the X-Button to insert a new weight.</string>
    <string name="help_a4_info">Opens the menu</string>

    <string name="help_b_title">B. Main graph information</string>
    <string name="help_b1_info">You see for what time span the graph is set (you can click on the graph to change between 7, 14 and 28 days view) The X-Axis is scaled in kg dependent on your weight.</string>
    <string name="help_b2_info">The blue line shows your weight over time, every number is your average daily weight.</string>
    <string name="help_b3_info">The bar charts show your daily calorie intake, they should stay below the red dotted line. The red dotted line is your approximated daily calorie burn rate.</string>
    <string name="help_b4_info">The Y-Axis is scaled by days 7/14/28 days range. (See point 1)</string>

    <string name="help_c_title">C. Main calendar information</string>
    <string name="help_c1_info">The calendar shows you your information in a 8 day view. Every row is an time period of 1 hour.\nEvery
        column is one day. Yellow areas represent times with at least 16 consecutive hours without calorie intake.\nThe numbers show
        how much calorie was taken in any given hour. The color shows (from green to red) shows the amount of calorie intake.\nThe
        Blue area is the current hour.</string>
    <string name="help_d_title">D. Insert new Meal Button</string>
    <string name="help_d1_info">On the main screen on the bottom right you can press this button to open a new insert window. There you can enter new calorie intake data.</string>

    <string name="help_e_title">E. Main menu information</string>
    <string name="help_e1_info">Opens the profile window. Here you can see and edit your personal data. (See point F)</string>
    <string name="help_e2_info">Opens the edit window. Here you can see and edit all your entered meal and weight data. (See point G)</string>
    <string name="help_e3_info">Opens a small information text about calorie deficit and the 16+8 approach.</string>
    <string name="help_e4_info">Opens the options window. Here you can turn on and off notifications and delete your data. (See point H)</string>

    <string name="help_f_title">F. Profile information</string>
    <string name="help_f1_info">Press the arrow to get back to the main screen.</string>
    <string name="help_f2_info">You can change the icon with a picture from your device, by pressing the picture.</string>
    <string name="help_f3_info">Information you entered when you started the App for the first time. (or edited it see point 5)</string>
    <string name="help_f4_info">A autogenerated text giving feedback over your progress.</string>
    <string name="help_f5_info">You can change your personal information by pressing this button.</string>

    <string name="help_g_title">G. Edit window</string>
    <string name="help_g1_info">Press the arrow to get back to the main screen.</string>
    <string name="help_g2_info">You can switch the shown data between your insert weight and meal data, by pressing the corresponding button.</string>
    <string name="help_g3_info">By pressing the blue area of the item you can edit the data. A dialog window will pop up.</string>
    <string name="help_g4_info">By pressing the red X you delete the item. The item will be deleted immediately without an other check.</string>


    <string name="help_h_title">H. Options window</string>
    <string name="help_h1_info">Press the arrow to get back to the main screen.</string>
    <string name="help_h2_info">With this switch you can enable or disable all notifications.</string>
    <string name="help_h3_info">Morning Reminder switch activates a morning notification.
        \nEvening summary switch activates a evening notification with some summary information.
        \nIf you activate any switch a button will appear, where you can individually set the time
        for the notification. (see second picture below)</string>
    <string name="help_h4_info">Deletes all your entered user and weight data.If you select it a warning message will ask you, if you really want to do it. Cant be undone.</string>
    <string name="help_h5_info">Button with becomes visible if you activate notification. You can press the button to extend a time picker to set an individual time for your notifications. (see point 6 and 7)</string>
    <string name="help_h6_info">Button with extend time picker view.</string>
    <string name="help_h7_info">Time picker to set the corresponding notification. Every notification has its own time picker. Only visible if notification is activated and you extend the view.</string>

    <string name="help_contact">If you have further questions or recommendations I would be happy the hear from you. Please leave a
        comment at the appstore you downloaded this app. More features will be added.\nThank you for using Weight Watch.</string>

    <!-- Notifications -->
    <string name="notification_morning_title">Good morning!</string>
    <string name="notification_morning_text"> Start your day with a smile and give your best!\nDon\'t forget to insert today\'s weight.</string>
    <string name="notification_evening_title">Good evening her is today\'s summary:</string>
    <string name="notification_evening_text">Today\'s Calorie Intake: %1$d calories\nCalorie Deficit: %2$d calories
        \nHave you entered all calorie data today? (Beverages, Snacks, Meals? You can simply enter the data retroactively if you forget it.)</string>
    <string name="notification_description">Your daily notification is scheduled to show at the specified time.
        However, please note that some devices restrict background services,
        which may affect the notification behavior. If you have trouble seeing your notifications, please check battery saver settings and enable autostart.
        We apologize if the notification doesn\'t show as intended on
        such devices.</string>



</resources>